you guys this looks like a fun one it
says find the area of the red region so
we want the area of the region contained
by these three circles and these circles
have a radius of one two and three
meters so for the first step let's
connect this Center to this Center and
then this Center to this Center and then
this Center to this Center this forms a
triangle and let's look at the triangle
down here so this is a radius of this
circle which is one and this is a radius
of this circle which is three which
makes this entire top side one plus
three which is four and same here this
is a radius of three and this is a
radius of two which would make this
whole bottom a length of five and then
this radius is two and this radius is
one which makes this side a length of
three so this is a three four five
triangle that is a Pythagorean triple
that means this has to be a right
triangle and here's the Pythagorean
theorem that verifies it all three four
five triangles are right triangles let's
find the area of this whole triangle the
area of a triangle is one half base
times height so if we rotate this thing
we can see that the base is four and the
height is three four times three is 12
and one half of 12 is 6. so the area of
this triangle is equal to 6. so now that
we have that let's look at these
individual pieces of the triangle we
have this yellow sector right here this
orange sector and the green sector let's
start by finding this orange piece if
this central angle is equal to D the
area of this sector is going to be equal
to D over 360 times pi r squared and we
know this is a right angle so that means
we can plug in 90 for the D and the
radius of the circle is equal to one so
we can plug in 1 for r 1 squared is
equal to one and multiplying by one we
don't need this one anymore 90 over 360
is equal to 1 4 so we end up with 1 4 Pi
or pi over four next we have the area of
this yellow sector let's make this angle
D degrees so we can use this formula
right here the radius of this circle is
equal to 3 and 3 squared is equal to
nine now we got to find the D let's copy
this triangle down again and this right
here is the angle D so now we have to
use some trigonometry we know that sine
of D is equal to the opposite over the
hypotenuse the side opposite of the D is
equal to 3 and hypotenuse is equal to
five so now to solve for D we need to do
the inverse of sine this sine inverse
gets rid of the sign so we just have D
on the left hand side and for the sine
inverse of three-fifths we can use a
calculator to get the approximate value
of this and we get 36.9 degrees and so
we can change this D into 36.9 so
fortunately this isn't exact anymore so
we got to make this an approximately
equal after we do all this math we get
the areas approximately 2.9 and last
let's do this green sector so we'll make
this angle right here D which means we
can use this formula again for the r the
radius of this circle is equal to 2 and
the 2 squared is equal to 4. and now to
find the D we know that the three angles
of a triangle add up to 180 degrees so
90 plus 36.9 plus d will equal 180. 90
plus 36.9 is 126.9 and after we subtract
that from both sides we get D is equal
to 53.1 and we can change this D into
53.1 and then once again we've got to
change this to approximate and after we
do this the area is approximately 1.9
and now we have everything we need to
find the area of this red region it's
going to be equal to this large triangle
minus the yellow region which was
approximately 2.9 but here's the exact
value right here minus the green region
which is approximately 1.9 but this is
the exact value for the green region and
then minus the pi over 4 which this is
the exact value and after we do all this
math we get approximately
0.464256 meters squared and these are
the answers to the question this is the
exact area and this is the approximate
area of the red region how exciting